<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Aaron James Young</title><link href="http://ajy.co/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://ajy.co/feed/personal.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://ajy.co/</id><updated>2013-10-31T19:30:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Hanna and Pumpkin</title><link href="http://ajy.co/personal/hanna-pumpkin" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-31T19:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.co,2013-10-31:personal/hanna-pumpkin</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Happy Halloween! Here's a quick shot of Hanna and the very basic pumpkin I carved for her this evening. Something tells me she wouldn't quite have the patience for something more complex (and neither would I, tonight).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yep, she's a bumblebee this year!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="family"></category><category term="hanna"></category><category term="holidays"></category></entry><entry><title>Fall in Salem</title><link href="http://ajy.co/personal/fall-in-salem" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-27T21:45:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.co,2013-10-27:personal/fall-in-salem</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The new site isn't 100% yet, but it's much better. I have some work to do on the post archive grids (you may have noticed).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it's almost bedtime, and I'm going to celebrate the new site by decorating it with this nice photo of a tree I took out our front window last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This fall's colors have been great - better than most falls because of our sunny weather with cool nights through October this year. Apparently that's great conditions for colorful leaves. However, we're going to start getting some more wind and rain soon, and the leaves will go away for the time being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading and enjoy the photo!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="salem"></category><category term="photo"></category><category term="fall"></category></entry><entry><title>The best coffee in Salem, Oregon</title><link href="http://ajy.co/personal/the-best-coffee-in-salem-oregon" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-26T14:23:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.co,2012-09-26:personal/the-best-coffee-in-salem-oregon</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It may be surprising, but we have a surprisingly good selection of
coffee here in Salem, Oregon. We have several quality coffee shops and
some great roasters in town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a few months now, we have been getting our coffee from Joseph Penner
at Steel Bridge Coffee - and it's the best coffee we've come across
here, for several reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steel Bridge is a completely &lt;a href="http://steelbridgecoffee.com"&gt;local coffee roasting company in Salem, Oregon&lt;/a&gt;. Joseph even roasts on a roaster built in Oregon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bicycle Delivery. Our coffee shows up every Tuesday afternoon on our
    doorstep in a jar and it's delivered by bicycle. How awesome is
    that?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As you know, the best coffee comes from the freshest beans. Joseph
    puts it best on his website: &lt;em&gt;"We bicycle-deliver whole bean coffee
    to your doorstep on the day that it was roasted (RAIN or SHINE)."&lt;/em&gt;
    Try finding coffee that fresh anyplace else in town.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality roasting. Joseph is a student of the craft and writes in
    detail about his &lt;a href="http://www.steelbridgecoffee.com/blog.html"&gt;coffee roasting experiences&lt;/a&gt; on his website. He
    buys and roasts coffee from various places around the world and is
    attentive to the differences  in coffee from region to region. He
    enjoys educating his customers about coffee as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cost: I can go to the grocery store and get a bag of coffee roasted
    three months ago if I'm lucky. Or I can get fresh roasted coffee
    delivered for almost the same price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph delivers whole bean coffee only. You'll need a grinder. If you
just use a drip machine, a blade grinder is adequate. But for more
flexibility (a French press is a great way to make coffee) you'll
definitely prefer spending a little extra on a decent burr grinder. A
burr grinder produces a much more even grind and I wouldn't use a French
press without it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you're in Salem, Oregon and you're trying to find the &lt;a href="http://steelbridgecoffee.com"&gt;best
coffee&lt;/a&gt; you can get in
your home or business, check out Steel Bridge Coffee and give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="coffee"></category><category term="coffee"></category><category term="delicious"></category></entry><entry><title>Want a free TV?</title><link href="http://ajy.co/personal/want-a-free-tv" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-12-20T16:59:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.co,2011-12-20:personal/want-a-free-tv</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edit: The TV is spoken for already. It took less than 10 minutes. That
was quick.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're going TV-free - and to celebrate, we're giving away a free TV (you
see what I did there?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You probably don't want this. It's not new, light, or sleek. It's one
more thing to use up space in your room and time in your life.
Hopefully, there's someone around you who is more important to you than
watching another sitcom on a standard-def, 27-inch CRT. Heck, in order
to even get over-the-air reception, you'll need to get one of those
analog-to-digital converter boxes. And an antenna.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully all this kind of explains why we're getting rid of it. To boil
it down, we just don't need it. We'd rather spend time with the baby and
each other. We don't particularly use it except for sports and
(sometimes) news, and those can be done on the computer if we need. At
some point we'll need to figure out how to handle the Olympics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we're really giving it away, but you'll need to act quickly if you do
want it (for whatever reason). Otherwise we'll be taking it to Goodwill
within the next couple days.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="free"></category></entry><entry><title>Baby announcements!</title><link href="http://ajy.co/personal/baby-announcements" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-05-10T07:42:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.co,2011-05-10:personal/baby-announcements</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://ajy.co/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/hanna.png" title="hanna" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other day, I made some baby announcements (finally)! We got them
printed up and we're getting them in the mail. If you aren't on our
mailing list, please admire the picture above instead or &lt;a href="http://ajy.co/contact-me"&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;
to request one.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="family"></category><category term="photo"></category></entry><entry><title>Updated workspace</title><link href="http://ajy.co/personal/updated-workspace" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-30T18:20:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.co,2011-01-30:personal/updated-workspace</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been updating my desk/work area:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://ajy.co/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/workspace-716x602.jpg" title="workspace" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo"></category></entry><entry><title>Letters to the Editor</title><link href="http://ajy.co/personal/letters-to-the-editor" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-10T12:41:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.co,2011-01-10:personal/letters-to-the-editor</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;OK, time for a quick fun post that has nothing to do with anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time, I've collected a few funny letters to the editor. All the
ones shown here are from the World in Coos Bay, Oregon. I decided it was
time to share some. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Letter 1: Editor is in the Jaws of Stupidity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Jaws of Stupidity" - now there's a good metaphor. I've got to remember
to use that one sometime. This letter, which appears to be in response
to an editorial by Kathy Erickson (the then-editor of the newspaper), is
very strongly written but doesn't really appear to say anything. Not
anything comprehensible, at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also worth noting: That wasn't a great day for letters all around. So
click the image below for BIGGER! I didn't want to crop out the other
letters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://ajy.co/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/stupidity-716x655.jpg" title="stupidity" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Letter 2: What really caused the Feb. 7th storm?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure what kind of world this guy thinks he lives in. I wonder
what Peter DeFazio thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://ajy.co/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/storm.jpg" title="storm" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Letter 3: Enjoying a sunny, soothing interlude&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah, a breath of fresh air and positivity in the midst of so much
turmoil. I'm glad this person is happy and carefree. I was just
thinking, when I wake up in the morning and I'm in a good mood, the
first thing I want to do is write a letter to the editor to tell 60,000
people that I'm happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://ajy.co/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/sun.jpg" title="sun" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Letter 4: A Bavarian eatery would be nice in North Bend&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems there's a fairly sizeable group of people in North Bend
(probably mostly in the 85+ age group) that feel that their city is
perfect and Coos Bay is constantly plotting to take over (consolidating
the two cities has appeared on several ballots and would probably make
economic sense for both cities and the larger region).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This person, though, has found something that North Bend needs: a
Bavarian restaurant. Apparently, they can prove that there is no
Bavarian restaurant by listing EVERY OTHER kind of restaurant that IS in
North Bend. The overall effect is that this person had a little trouble
staying on topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also note: Another bonus letter has been left un-blurred for you here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://ajy.co/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/bavarian.jpg" title="bavarian" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo"></category><category term="delicious"></category></entry><entry><title>O-Hana Salsa</title><link href="http://ajy.co/personal/o-hana-salsa" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-12-30T20:55:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.co,2010-12-30:personal/o-hana-salsa</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="O-Hana Salsa" src="http://ajy.co/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/salsa.jpg" title="O-Hana Salsa" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was at Fred Meyer a while back, and found O-Hana Salsa. It was on sale
and I noticed it's made in Bend, so I decided to try some.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's good stuff! The label doesn't look real great, and I'm not sure
what the name means, but the salsa itself is quite tasty. At this point,
I'm about ready to declare it the Official Salsa of Aaron James Young.
I'm sure they'll be thrilled.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="delicious"></category><category term="bend"></category></entry><entry><title>Cycling over Bear Camp Road</title><link href="http://ajy.co/personal/cycling-over-bear-camp-road" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-07-26T21:19:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.co,2010-07-26:personal/cycling-over-bear-camp-road</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, last Thursday I rode my bike from Gold Beach to Indian Mary Park,
near Merlin, near Grants Pass Oregon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was not easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit to add - if you're arriving at this article from an online search:
Bear Camp Road is a one and a half lane wide paved forest service road
between Agness, OR and Galice, OR. It follows a large ridge between
these two towns. It reaches an elevation of nearly 4,800 feet and should
not be traversed in the winter (though local people frequently travel
part of the distance to get to snow or for work-related reasons). During
the summer it recieves quite a bit of use from rafters and other people
traveling between Gold Beach and Grants Pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started at Gold Beach High School around 8:00 a.m. It was a beautiful
morning, but quite windy. I looped around the Gold Beach airstrip, up to
the highway, and out Jerry's Flat Road toward Agness. This is the route
used by the &lt;a href="http://goldbeachbiketherogue.org"&gt;Ride the Rogue&lt;/a&gt; event in September, which I can HIGHLY
recommend after doing this ride. This was my favorite part of the ride,
beautiful and a very rideable road. It's capped off near Agness with a
long (and fun) descent to a great bridge. The pavement is great for
riding, lots of patches but pretty smooth overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple miles after the bridge, I took a right turn on Bear Camp Road.
Here the fun begins. It's a 16-mile uphill from the river to the Bear
Camp overlook at around 4,800 feet up in the Klamath Mountains. There
are a lot of beautiful views but the miles tick by slowly. There are two
overlooks: the Siskiyou overlook about 10 miles up the hill (near
milepost 26; the mileposts are painted on the road and start at the
eastern end) and the Bear Camp overlook 16 miles up the hill (at
milepost 21). The road is windy and steep in places, with only a little
relief from time to time. Pavement is good, with some cracks &amp;amp; patches
but overall great for riding. There are a few very short gravel
stretches, maybe a total of 1/4 mile on gravel over the entire road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a nice stop at the Bear Camp Overlook (where I ate some food in
the car due to being bombed by gigantic flies) I took off for a 21-mile
mostly-downhill ride to the Galice area. There's a little uphill on this
stretch but nothing too bad. After a while I passed out of the Siskiyou
National Forest and the road goes to county maintenance, and the nice
smooth pavement changes over to a kind of rough chip seal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the downhill was great, but the worst part was from milepost 8
to milepost 4 where the road basically drops straight down the side of a
cliff (actually "straight" is a bad word, it's really curvy). I'm not
one to just coast down this kind of stuff at 50 mph, especially with the
chip seal, so I was leaning on the brakes for a while. After milepost 4
things get much better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hear talk of a "shoe tree" but didn't see it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pretty spent at the bottom of the hill but wanted to ride along
the Rogue River for a while again. It was hot enough, and I was sore
enough, that we decided to call it good at Indian Mary Park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total mileage: 72&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more time: See some pics! Click the "Photo Gallery" link at left.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="cycling"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="family"></category></entry><entry><title>Back from California!</title><link href="http://ajy.co/personal/back-from-california" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-10-07T18:15:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.co,2009-10-07:personal/back-from-california</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We're back from our California trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trip was a LOT of driving, but we saw lots of stuff. Most of my
pictures are of Red Rock Canyon state park in the Mojave Desert, and
Sequoia National Park. Evelyn and I skipped Yosemite this time -
probably not a good decision but we really needed to get home; and we'd
rather spend a little more time with Yosemite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, Californians were pretty rude on the road, but nice in person.
They were happy to help out an Oregonian who was having trouble pumping
gas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funniest vanity license plate: "THE NERD"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funniest city names: "Yreka" and "Chowchilla"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funniest city slogan: "Mojave: The Gateway to Space". I thought that was
a pretty bold claim - some towns are happy with just being the "gateway
to the coast".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biggest farm town in the world: Fresno (480,000 - the same size as
Sacramento)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most lacking: Coffee shops (it was pulling teeth to even find a
Starbucks in the whole state)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Replacement for coffee shops: Liquor stores, they're like coffee up
here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amount of fun it is to drive to LA on Dodger game night: Zero&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Number of rides at Six Flags Magic Mountain that Evelyn can do before
she gets sick: 3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Number of rides for Aaron: He didn't even try, he went to Red Rock
canyon instead where he could, well, stay on the ground&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miles logged: 2,300&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="family"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="california"></category></entry><entry><title>New plates!</title><link href="http://ajy.co/personal/new-plates" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-08-17T18:28:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.co,2009-08-17:personal/new-plates</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;![100_2060][]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;![100_2061][]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="photo"></category></entry><entry><title>Hot on the coast!</title><link href="http://ajy.co/personal/hot-on-the-coast" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-06-24T18:56:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.co,2009-06-24:personal/hot-on-the-coast</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This weather report was on the tv news this evening, then I went and
found it online at the National Weather Service's website:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;![screenshot_001][]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="unexpected"></category></entry><entry><title>Cereal Box Geography</title><link href="http://ajy.co/personal/cereal-box-geography" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-06-05T14:06:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.co,2009-06-05:personal/cereal-box-geography</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a picture from the back of the Fred Meyer Toasted Oats (also
known as generic Cheerios) box I got today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="america-not" src="http://ajy.co/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/america-not.jpg" title="america-not" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait a minute! That's not America!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry for bad picture quality, taken with cellphone camera.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="unexpected"></category><category term="photo"></category></entry><entry><title>Crisis averted</title><link href="http://ajy.co/personal/crisis-averted" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-04-28T21:37:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.co,2009-04-28:personal/crisis-averted</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, as of this morning the ham was gone from our stairs. While we're
relieved, we're not sure how or why it went away. We have a few ideas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was stolen (perhaps by the Hamburglar).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It gave up ("Look at all those stairs! I can't go up all those!").
    It took it a whole week to make it up one stair. I'm sure the ham
    wouldn't look too good by the time it got all the way up to our
    apartment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maybe it just changed its mind about wanting to stalk us...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, though, we can at least sleep at night without having to worry
about being attacked by meat.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="family"></category><category term="delicious"></category><category term="scary"></category></entry><entry><title>The Attack of the Ham</title><link href="http://ajy.co/personal/the-attack-of-the-ham" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-04-24T19:52:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.co,2009-04-24:personal/the-attack-of-the-ham</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, while I was gone over the weekend Evelyn came home to find a ham
sitting on the steps outside our apartment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="the-ham" src="http://ajy.co/wp-content/uploads/2009/04/the-ham.jpg" title="the-ham" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are a little mystified as to its origin; it has been sitting out
there for nearly a week now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today it moved up a step... we think it´s out to get us...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cue scary music!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="family"></category><category term="scary"></category><category term="delicious"></category></entry><entry><title>R2CB!</title><link href="http://ajy.co/personal/r2cb" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-04-22T10:37:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.co,2009-04-22:personal/r2cb</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Roseburg to Coos Bay Relay was last weekend. I ran on a team with my
family (all except David). Here's how things went:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drive to Coos Bay on Friday afternoon and watch the Coos County
    track meet. Eat some dinner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wake up at 4:00 a.m. This run had better be a LOT of fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leave at 4:30 a.m. to drive to Roseburg in time for our 7:00 start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start! My mom takes leg 1 out toward Lookingglass in the cool
    overcast weather. At least it's dry. Leg 1 is mostly uphill.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We see a jeep drive by like three times during leg 2 (Dad) and leg 3
    (Steph). On my leg (4), I see it being towed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I run leg 4. Still cloudy and cold. Leg 4 is flat at first, then
    starts going up... it goes up for a while, then downhill, then up
    again on a steeper hill. Overall not an easy leg, but I felt pretty
    good and did fine powering up the hill.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corey has leg 5. Ha ha ha ha ha! This is a nasty hill.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mom takes over on leg 6. This finishes off the hill from leg 5 and
    then goes downhill on the other side. The Coquille River starts up
    here, as a little trickle becoming a stream. The road changes to
    gravel and the clouds cleared off on this leg. For the rest of the
    run, it was sunny and really warm, although it cooled off a bit as
    we approached the coast of course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As Dad is running leg 7, we're driving down the gravel road in the
    middle of the forest, with waterfalls along the ever-growing
    Coquille River.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We pick up some pavement on Steph's downhill leg 8.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My leg 9 is flat, short, and hot. I didn't feel very good on this
    one. Not looking forward to the next one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After Corey's leg, Mom has a fun leg: 2 miles up, 2 miles down.
    Another runner was looking at the gentle slope rising from the
    exchange point, she said, "is it like this the whole way up?" Not
    really... she reaches the top of the hill spewing expletives... Mom
    says, "well, the last half mile was pretty steep, I guess".&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fairview! Everyone's stopping at the store since it's the first one
    we've seen for hours. But Coos Bay is just over the hill..&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Up Blue Ridge, and down the other side on the gravel road to Sumner.
    Almost time for me to run my third leg...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I get to run my last leg on the rolling hills from Sumner to the big
    hill I used to run several times a week to get to my house... I felt
    great, charged over the top of the big hill and down Ross Inlet
    Road.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corey finishes off by running into Eastside then Coos Bay and
    finishing at Freddy's.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time to get some 'za at Abby's. We were third in our division in
    9:27:26.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="leg-comments" src="http://ajy.co/wp-content/uploads/2009/04/leg-comments-300x225.jpg" title="leg-comments" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="family"></category><category term="running"></category><category term="travel"></category></entry><entry><title>Charm of Hate</title><link href="http://ajy.co/personal/charm-of-hate" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-04-09T21:03:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.co,2009-04-09:personal/charm-of-hate</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We were just watching Wheel of Fortune. In the final round, the guy had
to guess the phrase from the following letters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R -    - -    - - T E&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He guessed "Charm of Hate".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(the correct answer was "Quirk of Fate")&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="unexpected"></category></entry><entry><title>New Salem bridge!</title><link href="http://ajy.co/personal/new-salem-bridge" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-04-09T11:24:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.co,2009-04-09:personal/new-salem-bridge</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="bridge1" src="http://ajy.co/wp-content/uploads/2009/04/bridge1.jpg" title="bridge1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old railroad bridge over the Willamette River has been converted to
a pedestrian/bike bridge and is open now! It connects Riverfront Park
and Wallace Marine Park. Riverfront Park is a grassy park with a
carousel and wide concrete walking paths, and lots of community
festivals and things are held there; Wallace Marine is a little more
wild and has a reputation as the location of several homeless camps.
Hopefully the increased foot and bike traffic in the area - along with
city and volunteer efforts to clean out some undergrowth and maintain
running trails in the park - will make the park a more pleasant place to
be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the bridge isn't much of a looker, but it's nice to
have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="bridge2" src="http://ajy.co/wp-content/uploads/2009/04/bridge2.jpg" title="bridge2" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though it doesn't look beautiful from a distance, it's not
unpleasant when you're there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="bridge3" src="http://ajy.co/wp-content/uploads/2009/04/bridge3.jpg" title="bridge3" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a lead paint issue on the bridge, it's flaking off on places
like this. It's been sealed 6-8 feet above the walkway, the picture here
shows an area above that. As far as I know, the bridge will be closed
over next winter so the issue can be taken care of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey, Salem's got something cool now! In your FACE, Bend!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="salem"></category></entry><entry><title>Fruit on the Bottom - a yogurt review</title><link href="http://ajy.co/personal/fruit-on-the-bottom-a-yogurt-review" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-03-06T12:09:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.co,2009-03-06:personal/fruit-on-the-bottom-a-yogurt-review</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I sit here eating a cup of yogurt, it occurs to me: Who invented
fruit-on-the-bottom yogurt? Is it good? Of course, I have an opinion
about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I'm not generally an "instant-gratification,
I-want-everything-right-now" kind of guy. But I can't help but think
that the fruit is put on the bottom &lt;em&gt;simply to add an extra layer of
preparation before I can enjoy my yogurt&lt;/em&gt;. I not only have to remove the
lid and weird little foil thing, I have to stir the fruit into the
yogurt. Sometimes, I rush the stirring a little too much, and end up
spilling a glob of yogurt on the table, floor, or myself (yeah, I can
hear you snickering already. This is purely an indictment of the yogurt
companies, or as I call them, "Big Yogurt"; this has nothing to do with
my strengths and weaknesses as a yogurt stirrer). Let's face it:
Fruit-on-the-bottom is a poor user interface design for yogurt cups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what's the point anyway? If I stir the fruit into the yogurt, I've
just spent an extra 30 seconds to bring my yogurt up to "blended yogurt"
standards. The stirring (in my opinion) ruins the consistency and
temperature of the yogurt and it's impossible to stir it up evenly
anyways. There's always too much fruit left in the bottom. If I wanted
my yogurt and fruit separate, I'd eat a bunch of plain yogurt then a
couple spoonfuls of jam or a pineapple or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am only one voice, but if enough of us speak up, Big Yogurt will
eventually have to listen.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="rant"></category><category term="delicious"></category></entry><entry><title>Ants are bad.</title><link href="http://ajy.co/personal/ants-are-bad" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-07-14T19:20:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.co,2008-07-14:personal/ants-are-bad</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've been fighting sugar ants for several days now. They're on the
verge of being quite a problem, and we are having a tough time staying
on top of them. I told Evelyn that we really need to think about a
different kind of pet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Yes", she said. "An anteater."&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="family"></category></entry><entry><title>We're back!</title><link href="http://ajy.co/personal/were-back" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-06-17T18:11:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.co,2008-06-17:personal/were-back</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We're back from our trip to Bend. It was a great trip. The weather was
amazing (80's and sunny the whole time) and Bend seems like a pretty
cool town. We have a few pictures up, just click "pictures" above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a quick run-down of the trip (links are to Google maps of
trails):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday: After arriving in Bend, we ran the &lt;a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;geocode=&amp;amp;q=bend,+oregon&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ll=44.067842,-121.313653&amp;amp;spn=0.001742,0.003315&amp;amp;t=h&amp;amp;z=18" title="Map to trailhead"&gt;First Street Rapids
trail&lt;/a&gt;. This starts just a few blocks from downtown and is a
dirt/gravel trail along the Deschutes river with views of mountains.
Bend has lots of these kinds of trails within a few minutes of town.
Thursday's dinner was at the McMenamin's downtown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday's coffee was Bend Mountain Coffee. The run was at&lt;a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;geocode=&amp;amp;q=bend,+oregon&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ll=44.083115,-121.377876&amp;amp;spn=0.003484,0.00663&amp;amp;t=h&amp;amp;z=17" title="Map to trailhead"&gt;Shevlin
Park&lt;/a&gt;, a city park along the west end of town. It's got trails through
the forest and feels further out than it really is. Dinner was Pizza
Mondo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday's coffee was Maui Wowi (yes, that's what it is really called).
Good coffee! Evelyn ran a trail from Larkspur Park to &lt;a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;geocode=&amp;amp;q=bend,+oregon&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ll=44.060915,-121.282411&amp;amp;spn=0.013939,0.026522&amp;amp;t=h&amp;amp;z=15"&gt;Pilot Butte&lt;/a&gt;,
then up the butte, then cooled down back to the park. Again, it's cool
that Bend has these trails in town. Dinner was... let's see... dinner
was Bella Cucina, a little Italian restaurant in the Old Mill District.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunday's coffee was the Strictly Organic Coffee House. We ran at Shevlin
Park again and stopped for smoothies from Maui Wowi on our way back into
town. Dinner was Toomie's, a Thai restaurant downtown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monday's coffee was Backporch Coffee. They roast their own coffee and
have some interesting blends. We ran on the &lt;a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;geocode=&amp;amp;q=bend,+oregon&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ll=43.99726,-121.385225&amp;amp;spn=0.003489,0.00663&amp;amp;t=h&amp;amp;z=17" title="Map to trailhead"&gt;Deschutes River Trail&lt;/a&gt;
south of town. This was only a 10-minute drive from town! Shevlin Park
was even closer. Did I mention that we were impressed with how much
trail running there is in Bend? Dinner was at a seafood chain restaurant
called Anthony's. It was nice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuesday's coffee was Bellatazza. We then packed our stuff and left town.
On the way back, we stopped in Sisters and ran the &lt;a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;geocode=&amp;amp;q=bend,+oregon&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ll=44.284007,-121.549644&amp;amp;spn=0.003472,0.00663&amp;amp;t=h&amp;amp;z=17" title="Map to trailhead"&gt;Eagle Rock Loop&lt;/a&gt;.
And now we're home! And it's cloudy again!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bend"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="travel"></category></entry></feed>