<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Aaron James Young</title><link href="http://ajy.dev/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://ajy.dev/feed/portfolio.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://ajy.dev/</id><updated>2013-01-29T21:25:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>Skyline Baptist Church</title><link href="http://ajy.dev/portfolio/skyline-baptist-church" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-29T21:25:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.dev,2013-01-29:portfolio/skyline-baptist-church</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://sbcnb.org"&gt;Visit Skyline Baptist Church&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skyline Baptist Church is a medium-sized Baptist church located in North Bend, Oregon (in the Coos Bay area). Skyline asked me to create a responsive, attractive website based on Wordpress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new website is responsive and will adapt to the screen size of any device used to view the site; and the Wordpress backend allows the church staff to maintain and update content on the site, including an advanced calendar and sermon podcasting system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wordpress theme is custom-coded (as are all my themes) and is search engine-friendly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a fun project to build for a great client. Church websites are tricky to get right - there are many needs and a content strategy is key. I'm happy with how this one turned out!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Bethany Baptist Church</title><link href="http://ajy.dev/portfolio/bethany-baptist-church" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-31T20:01:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.dev,2012-05-31:portfolio/bethany-baptist-church</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://bethanybaptistchurch.com"&gt;Visit Bethany Baptist Church&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a member of Bethany Baptist Church in Salem, Oregon, I was excited to
have a chance to redesign their website. Bethany Baptist is a
medium-sized church located in south Salem. The website is built with a
custom-designed Wordpress theme. It uses responsive design, meaning the
site layout will adapt to various mobile devices with different screen
sizes. "Pinch to zoom" not required!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site uses advanced CSS/Javascript menus that are
touchscreen-friendly, customized Wordpress plugins for the events
calendar and other functions, and a search engine-friendly Wordpress
template.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Oregon Travel Experience</title><link href="http://ajy.dev/portfolio/oregon-travel-experience" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-30T20:38:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.dev,2012-05-30:portfolio/oregon-travel-experience</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ortravelexperience.com"&gt;Visit Oregon Travel Experience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not design the website for Oregon Travel Experience. Instead, OTE
already had a complete design provided to them. I planned and created a
complete Wordpress theme and custom coding to implement the design into
a working website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oregon Travel Experience is a semi-independent state agency that manages
travel-related services throughout Oregon. OTE administers the Heritage
Tree and Historical Marker programs as well as providing the blue
highway signs with business logos. They provide many other services
around the state as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OTE was previously known as the Oregon Travel Information Council but
went through an extensive rebranding process which included the new logo
and website design. The OTIC still exists as the administrative body for
OTE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website features a jQuery slider on the home page, a customized
mapping plugin, and a design that reflows to fit smartphone screens,
eliminating "Pinch to zoom".&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>YWCA - Salem, Oregon</title><link href="http://ajy.dev/portfolio/ywca-salem-oregon" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-29T20:55:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.dev,2012-05-29:portfolio/ywca-salem-oregon</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href="http://ywcasalem.org"&gt;YWCA - Salem, Oregon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Salem, Oregon affiliate of the YWCA approached &lt;a href="http://opt-e-web.com"&gt;Opt-e-Web&lt;/a&gt; for a
new website design last winter. I designed and developed this site as
Design Director for Opt-e-Web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The design carefully follows national YWCA branding guidelines. The new
website highlights the programs and services provided by the YWCA and is
easily editable by the client through Wordpress.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Opt-e-Web</title><link href="http://ajy.dev/portfolio/opt-e-web" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-11-26T14:51:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Aaron James Young</name></author><id>tag:ajy.dev,2011-11-26:portfolio/opt-e-web</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://opt-e-web.com"&gt;Visit Opt-e-Web.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am the website design director for Opt-e-Web, a web and tech agency in
Salem. Opt-e-Web provides these services:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://designsalem.com"&gt;Website design and development, and graphic design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://opt-e-web.com/seomarketing"&gt;Web marketing and SEO services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://itservicessalem.com"&gt;IT and computer services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opt-e-Web generally works with clients in northwest and central Oregon,
including Salem, Portland, and Bend. We also work with some clients
outside these areas, including one in the UK - so feel free to give us a
call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is our current website, but I've got another one cooking that will be launched soon. The new
site will be responsive and generally cleaner.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>